<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homes on Academic</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/home/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homes on Academic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/home/about/</guid>
      <description>Biography My PhD research involved large scale analyses to understand the regulation of alternative splicing in cancer. Alternative splicing is a mechanism that produces different proteins from same gene sequence and almost 95% of genes in humans undergo this process. However, in diseases like cancer this process produces disease variant of normal protein. We worked with RNAseq data of more than 4000 patients and 18 different tumor types, along with whole genome sequencing data of &amp;gt;400 patients to produce pan-cancer analysis of splicing changes and its regulation both at cis (mutations on DNA) and trans (differential expression of genes) levels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selected Publications</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/home/publications_selected/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/home/publications_selected/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent Publications</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/home/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/home/publications/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/home/learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/home/learning/</guid>
      <description>Here I am listing few materials that I utilized during my PhD. I have deep gratitude for people who develop Open-source softwares and those who provide knowledge for free, from cooking hacks to app development everything is just a Youtube search away.
Few basic tools required for bioinformatics research:
Programming  R
When I started my PhD I started with languages that I thought will be enough: Perl, C, C++, English.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selected Talks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/home/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/home/talks/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Entrepreneur</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/home/entrepreneurship/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/home/entrepreneurship/</guid>
      <description>In the beginning of 2018, I received an Erasmus Young Entrepreneurship award to learn social entrepreneurship. My interest in psychology, society and sewing lead me to work with a non-profit called Made in Carcere (Made in Prison). From six months I have been working inside maximum security prison in Italy with male and female detainees, together we design &amp;amp; develop fashion accessories such as handbags and t-shirts. It is an ongoing, life changing experience that I am observing in real-time, Among other things I am learning 1) how businesses run, 2) how prisons run and 3) how human psychology runs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Procrastination</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/home/procrastination/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/home/procrastination/</guid>
      <description>Once during a beer session, I overheard a conversation between two (extremely motivated) academics, &amp;ldquo;if you&amp;rsquo;re doing something that does not directly contributes to your research, you&amp;rsquo;re procrastinating&amp;rdquo;. So, this is my selected list of &amp;lsquo;procrastination&amp;rsquo;, they kept me inspired.
Science &amp;amp; Philosophy A Short History of Nearly Everything Most people start their journey towards science with this book but I read it quite late. This book was gifted to me from my PI when I defended my thesis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expressions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/home/expression/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/home/expression/</guid>
      <description>This section talks about personal expressions I discovered through art, travel and dancing.
If done right, traveling puts all four psychological functions of an individual at work, I discovered this while discovering Europe (shout-out to Schengen!). Europe is pure art no matter which corner I turned, so best way to travel was to stop planning and start exploring. One summer backpacking from south of France to north of Italy, I reached Perinaldo, birth town of Cassini, just like that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/home/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/home/contact/</guid>
      <description>Please drop a line at this mail id for:
 cool project collaborations related with science, creativity, genomics, neuroscience, psychology, AI. prison stories or why I escaped. guidelines for an unplanned trip to Camino de Santiago cultural changes and how to stay objective Jungian psychology, darkness of depression my preferred list of podcasts trick I discovered (finally) to learn new languages  or just say hello:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>